A Guide to the Gubernatorial Appointments of the Virginia Secretary of Commonwealth, 1994-2017 (bulk 2002-2008)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Gubernatorial Appointments of the Virginia Secretary of Commonwealth, 1994-2017 (bulk 2002-2008)
The Library of Virginia
53506
5.85 cu.ft. (17 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The folders must be reviewed before being served. Privacy protected information is considered closed for 75 years after date of record creation per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: forms with birth dates and social security numbers and resumes.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 7 January 2022 by the Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1111 East Broad Street, 4th Floor, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Historical Information
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. Thomas Nelson held the position of the first Secretary of Virginia in 1776. Early Secretaries were elected by the public. An Act of the General Assembly in 1920 changed the election to a joint vote of the General Assembly. In a 1930 Act the duties of the Secretary were redefined with the Secretary of the Commonwealth serving as the ex officio secretary of the Governor, as custodian of many official State records, and as keeper of the Greater and Lesser Seals of the Commonwealth. The office of the Secretary has gradually acquired other functions, such as: service of out-of-state civil process; appointment and regulation of notaries public; and registration and oversight of lobbyists. The Office became a gubernatorial appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office. The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Additional activities include: serving as ex officio Secretary to the Governor; serving as keeper of the seals of the Commonwealth; compiling and publishing the annual Blue Book; commissioning and regulating notary publics, including the publication of a Notary Handbook and conduct of disciplinary hearings; promulgating the lobbying disclosure requirements, registration of lobbyists, and recording of lobbying reports; servicing the civil process of out-of-state defendants and other parties; and authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
Gubernatorial appointments, 1994-2017 (bulk 2002-2008), to state boards and commissions during the administrations of Governor George Allen (1994-1998), Governor James S. Gilmore (1998-2002), Governor Mark Warner (2002-2006), Governor Tim Kaine (2006-2010), Governor Robert McDonnell (2010-2014), and Governor Terry McAuliffe (2014-2018). Includes appointment sheets, correspondence, curriculum vitae and resumes, press releases, and financial disclosure statements. The bulk of the appointments were from Governor Mark Warner and Governor Tim Kaine's terms.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into subcategories by agency and then alphabetically thereunder. Original order was maintained.
Contents List
- Administration, Arts and Architectural Review Board, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Administration, Citizen's Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion, 2003-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Administration, Commonwealth Competition Council, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Administration, Information Technology Investment Board, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Administration, State Board of Elections, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administration, Virginia Geographic Information Network Advisory Board, 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Administration, Wireless E-911 Services Board, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Agricultural and Consumer Services Board, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Aquaculture Advisory Board, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Charitable Gaming Board, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Forestry Board, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Milk Commission, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Agriculture Council, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia ABC Board, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Cattle Industry Board, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Corn Board, 2006-2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Cotton Board, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Egg Board, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Horse Industry Board, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Irish Potato Board, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Marine Products Board, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Peanut Board, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Pork Industry Board, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Racing Commission, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Soybean Board, 2006-2013 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Agriculture and Forestry, Virginia Wine Board, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Commerce and Trade, Apprenticeship Council, 2006-2008, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Architects, Professional Engineers, Land Surveyors, Certified Interior Designers, and Landscape Architects, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Commerce and Trade, Auctioneers Board, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Barbers and Cosmetology, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Commerce and Trade, Cemetery Board, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Commerce and Trade, Center for Rural Virginia Board of Trustees, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Coal Mining Examiners, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Commerce and Trade, Coal Surface Mining Reclamation Fund Advisory Board, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Commerce and Trade, Commission on Local Government, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Commerce and Trade, Common Interest Community Board, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Contractors, 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Commerce and Trade, Fair Housing Board, 2003-2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Commerce and Trade, Hampton Roads Sanitation District Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Hearing Aid Specialists, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Commerce and Trade, Housing and Community Development, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Commissioners of the Virginia Housing Development Authority, 2005-2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Commerce and Trade, Latino Advisory Board, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Commerce and Trade, Northern Virginia Transportation Authority, 2004-2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Professional and Occupational Regulation, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Professional Soil Scientists and Wetland Professionals, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Commerce and Trade, Real Estate Appraiser Board, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Commerce and Trade, Real Estate Board, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Directors Richmond Eye and Ear Hospital Authority, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Commerce and Trade, Safety and Health COdes Board, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Commerce and Trade, Small Business Advisory Board, 2005-2008 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Commerce and Trade, Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Visitors Virginia Biotechnology Research Park Authority, 2002-2008 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Board for Asbestos, Lead, and Home Inspectors, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of the Virginia Coalfield Economic Development Authority, 2001-2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Coal Mine Safety Board, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Directors Virginia Economic Development Partnership, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Gas and Oil Board, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia-Israel Advisory Board, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Manufactured Housing Board, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Recreational Authority, 1999-2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Directors of the Virginia Resources Authority, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Sheep Industry Board, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Small Grains Board, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Commerce and Trade, Board of Directors Virginia Tourism Authority, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Commerce and Trade, Board for Waterworks and Wastewater Works Operators and Onsite Sewage System Professionals, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Commerce and Trade, Virginia Workforce Council, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Compacts, Breaks Interstate Park Commission, 2005-2008 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Compacts, Citizens Advisory Committee to the Chesapeake Executive Council, 2002-2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Compacts, Live Horseracing Compact Committee, 2004-2008 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Compacts, Education Commission of the States, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Compacts, Governor's Mined Land Reclamations Advisory Committee, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Compacts, Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin, 2002-2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Compacts, Legislative Advisory Council, Southern Regional Education Board, 2004-2008 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Compacts, Local Government Advisory Committee, Chesapeake Bay Program, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Compacts, Metropolitan Washington Airport's Authority, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Compacts, New Economy Workforce Council, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Compacts, Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Compacts, Southeast Low-Level Radioactive Waste Management Compact Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Compacts, Southern Regional Education Board, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Compacts, Southern Technology Council, 2004-2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Compacts, State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Compacts, Virginia Roanoke River Bi-State Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Designated, Board of Commissioners of Vint Hill Economic Development Authority, 1998-2008 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Designated, Poet Laureate, 1999-2008 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Education, Board of Trustees A.L. Philpott Manufacturing Extension Partnership, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Christopher Newport University, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Education, Board of Education, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Education, Board of Trustees, Frontier Culture Museum of Virginia, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Education, Board of Visitors, George Mason University, 2006-2009 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Gunston Hall, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Education, Board of Trustees, Institute for Advanced Learning and Research, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Education, Board of Visitors, James Madison University, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Education, Board of Trustees, Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Education, Library Board, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Longwood University, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Education, Board of Directors, New College Institute, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Norfolk State University, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Old Dominion University, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Radford University, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Education, Roanoke Higher Education Center Board of Trustees, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Education, Southern Virginia Higher Education Center Board of Trustees, 2005-2009 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Education, Southwest Virginia Higher Education Center Board of Trustees 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Education, Science Museum of Virginia Board of Trustees, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Education, State Board of Community Colleges, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Education, State Certified Seed Bank, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Education, State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Education, State Historical Records Advisory Board, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Education, Board of Visitors, University of Mary Washington, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Education, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, 2006-2012 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Education, Virginia Commission of the Arts, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Education, Virginia Commission on Higher Education Board Appointments, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Virginia Commonwealth University, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Virginia Military Institute, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Education, Board of Trustees, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Virginia State University, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Education, Board of Visitors, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Education, Board of Visitors, College of William and Mary, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Executive, Commission on Higher Education Reform, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Executive, Governor's Advisory Board on Service and Volunteerism, 2007-2010 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Executive, Governor's Advisory Board on Service and Volunteerism, 2010-2012 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Executive, Governor's Commission on Military and National Security Facilities, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Executive, Governor's Economic Development and Jobs Creation Commission, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Executive, Governor's Teacher Cabinet, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Finance, Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Finance, Council on Virginia's Future, 2003-2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Finance, Debt Capacity Advisory Board, 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Finance, Treasury Board, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Finance, Board of the Virginia College Building Authority, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Finance, Board of the Virginia Public Building Authority, 2002-2007 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Finance, Board of the Virginia Public Building Authority, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Acupuncture, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Health and Human Resources, Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Directors for the Assistive Technology Loan Fund Authority, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Athletic Training, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Health and Human Resources, Child Support Guideline Review Panel, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Health and Human Resources, Commonwealth Council on Aging, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Health and Human Resources, Commonwealth Neurotrauma Initiative Advisory Board, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Health and Human Resources, Community Integration Advisory Commission, 2006-2009 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Counseling, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Dentistry, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Trustees for thr Family and Children's Trust Fund, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Health Professions, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Long-Term Care Administrators 2008 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Medical Assistance Services, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Medicine, 2006-2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Midwifery, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Nursing, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Occupational Therapy, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Optometry, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Pharmacy, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Physical Therapy, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Physician Assistants, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Psychology, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Health and Human Resources, Public Guardian and Conservator Advisory Board, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Radiological Technology, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board on Respiratory Care, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Social Services, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Social Work, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Health and Human Resources, State Child Fatality Review Team, 2006-2008 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Health and Human Resources, State Emergency Medical Services Advisory Board, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Health and Human Resources, State Emergency Medical Services Advisory Board, 2008-2009 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Health and Human Resources, State Board of Health, 2006-2010 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Health and Human Resources, State Health Department Sewage Handling and Disposal Appeal Review Board, 1994, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Health and Human Resources, State Rehabilitation Advisory Council, 2007-2008 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Veterinary Medicine, 2006-2008 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Health and Human Resources, Virginia Board for People with Disabilities, 2005-2008 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
- Health and Human Resources, Advisory Board for the Virginia Department for the Deaf and Hard-of-Hearing, 2006-2008 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Health and Human Resources, Board of Trustees of the Virginia Tobacco Settlement Foundation, 2006-2008 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Independent, Chesapeake Bay Bridge and Tunnel Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Independent, Reading First Reading and Literacy Partnership, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Independent, Scientific and Technical Advisory Committee to the Chesapeake Bay Executive Council, 2006-2007 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Independent, State Lottery Board, 2002-2007 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Independent, Tennessee Valley Authority Regional Resource Stewardship Council, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Independent, Tobacco Settlement Financing Corporation, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Independent, United Nations Day in Virginia, 2006-2008 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Independent, Board of Directors, Virginia Birth-Related Neurological Injury Compensation Program, 2002-2008 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Independent, Board of Virginia College Savings Plan, 2006-2008 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Independent, Virginia Commonwealth University Health Systems Authority, Board of Directors, 2002-2007 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Independent, Virginia Retirement System, Board of Trustees, 2002-2008 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Independent, Volunteer Firefighters and Rescue Squad Worker's Service Award Pension Fund, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Judicial, Escheator, 2002-2005 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Judicial, Indigent Defense Commission, 2004-2007 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Judicial, Virginia Criminal Sentencing Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Legislative, Brown V. Board of Education Scholarship Awards Committee, 2004-2007 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Legislative, Capitol Square Preservation Council, 2003-2008 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Legislative, Manufacturing Development Commission, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Legislative, Small Business Commission, 2003-2008 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Legislative, State Water Commission, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Legislative, Commissioners for the Promotion of Uniformity of Legislation, 2004-2008 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Legislative, Virginia Coal and Energy Commission, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Legislative, Virginia Code Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Legislative, Virginia Commission on Youth, 2002-2008 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Legislative, Virginia Freedom of Information Advisory Council, 2003-2007 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Legislative, Virginia Housing Commission, 2002-2008 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Legislative, Virginia State Crime Commission, 2004-2008 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Legislative, Council on the Status of Women, 2005-2008 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Natural Resources, Alexandria Historical and Preservation Commission, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Natural Resources, Cave Board, 2003-2008 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Natural Resources, Board of Conservation and Recreation, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Natural Resources, Board of Game and Inland Fisheries, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Natural Resources, Board of Historic Resources, 1998-2008 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Natural Resources, Litter Control and Recycling Fund Advisory Board, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Natural Resources, Board of Visitors to Mount Vernon, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Natural Resources, Soil and Water Conservation Board, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Natural Resources, State Air Pollution Control Board, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Natural Resources, State Water Control Board, 2003-2008 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Coastal Land Management Advisory Council, 2002-2004 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Land Conservation Foundation, 2002-2008 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Marine Resources Commission, 1998-2008 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Outdoors Foundation, 2002-2008 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Waste Management Board, 2002-2008 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Natural Resources, Virginia Water Resources Research Center Statewide Advisory Board, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Public Safety, Citizen-Soldier Support Council, 2007-2008 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Public Safety, Commission on Climate Change, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Public Safety, Board of Corrections, 2006-2009 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Public Safety, Criminal Justice Services Board, 2006-2008 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Public Safety, Governor's Motorcycle Advisory Council, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Public Safety, Advisory Committee on Juvenile Justice, 2006-2007 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Public Safety, Scientific Advisory Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Public Safety, Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2005-2008 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Public Safety, Special Advisory Commission on Mandated Health Insurance Benefits, 2006-2008 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Public Safety, Virginia Fire Services Board, 2006-2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Transportation, Aerospace Advisory Council, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Transportation, Commonwealth Transportation Board, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Transportation, Commonwealth Transportation Board, 2005-2010 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Transportation, Medical Advisory Board for the Department of Motor Vehicles, 2002-2008 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Transportation, Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Transportation, Motor Vehicle Dealer Board, 2002-2007 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Transportation, Virginia Aviation Board, 2002-2008 (Box 16, Folder 10)